it's either like digital nomadism is
the future and like the best way of life
or it's like digital nomadism is for self-obsessed
millennials that can't like get a job right it's
either like this is amazing and the best
thing for the future or terrible and like
no one should do it and actually you'll hate
it if you try it hello and welcome to lewis and
kyle show an interview podcast where lewis and i
interview high performers entrepreneurs investors
makers people just doing really unconventional and
interesting things and today we have steph smith
on the podcast steph is hard to describe she does
so many things in her day job she leads trends.co
which is a newsletter product brought to you by
the hustle sends out really awesome weekly emails
about new and exciting business opportunities
via email and to their paid community which
actually is a pretty high track record of people
taking ideas and starting successful businesses
based on the reports that she finds she's
a self-taught programmer and indie hacker
she's a popular blogger she's the author of how to
do content right and she has been a digital nomad
for about five years this episode steph joins
us to discuss how in her day job she finds and
exploits new business opportunities how she helps
us live brainstorm a couple business ideas just to
see her idea muscles in action she gives us the
do's and don'ts of long-term digital nomadism
and she also discusses many other things but most
notably balancing tracking habits with becoming an
insane self-obsessed person who's obsessed with
numbers and how to do that in like a healthy and
productive way i really enjoyed this conversation
i'm excited for you to listen to it but
before we get into it if you're new to the podcast
make sure you're subscribed if you're old listener
and you haven't told a friend about the show
and you've been enjoying it now today like any
other day great opportunity go on twitter go on
instagram go on facebook press that share button
and say hey you'll love these guys lewis and kyle
help us out if we've been adding value that's all
we ask with that let's switch over to the episode
with steph enjoy beth welcome to the lewis and
kyle show we have been super excited for this
conversation we're excited it's finally happening
thanks for having me absolutely i want to
ask you an interesting variant of our typical
opening question if how would you introduce
yourself without talking about your job
oh that's such a good question because i feel
like any time you describe yourself you're
just you're just saying labels like i'm
a writer i'm a maker i'm something um
i guess if i weren't to talk about specifically
what i do i always like to say that
i just follow my curiosities whether it's
through my job or elsewhere and i actually
really like that question because again i think
a lot of the time we tie ourselves or our work
to our identities and then get fixated on that
and forever follow that path instead of just
following things that truly make you curious and
that you want to wake up to and work on every day
yeah i love that question and it was one of the
things that i i explained it to louis earlier on i
think you termed it enmeshment where you you sort
of become your job and i think that's only gotten
worse as time's gotten on with um with covert and
everything but your job is is really really cool
so you can will you tell us a little bit
about that as well yeah and just speaking
quickly to what you mentioned i think this idea
of enmeshment and becoming your career is the way
i like to articulate it is you basically start
out in life and early on like when you're 15 no
one knows what they want to do they might think
they know what they want to do and then you just
start walking up a hill and then five years later
you realize you're walking up this hill and you
see other hills out there but you're already
halfway up the hill that you've already started on
and you have this like sunk cost fallacy where
you're like i'm not gonna turn around go all the
way down this hill and climb up another one um
so i and then we just become tied to that hill
right forever and we never actually turn around
but speaking of my job i i work on this product
called trends at the hustle uh it's trends.com we
basically sounds exactly how it's named we find
friends before they're happening or as they're on
the up we share them with people who subscribe to
trends and then we have a community kind of tacked
onto that and a couple other features but really
it's just so that people whether your business
operator investor um someone who just finds
this stuff interesting can get ahead of the game
and um yeah be a little bit ahead of the curve
compared to the rest of the world great i've been
a little confused when you say that you're the
head of it does that mean you're you're you're the
writer or you have a team of writers or oh it's
yeah you want to thread and you're like all right
tell me more about this what does that mean to
like head the project it's so it's such a silly
title um but it's really because i so i lead the
product it's like saying like you're the general
manager but i just think general manager sounds a
little too fancy makes me think of a hotel yeah so
i i guess i used to when i first started at trends
write trends so i started as what we call a senior
analyst and i was responsible for writing trends
for almost a year and then i switched to leading
the product and and really focusing on the product
and growth side of things so i guess you could
call me a product manager that's probably the more
um consistent term in the industry but yeah
i basically lead the product i work with the
analysts i work with you know our growth guys
who actually are working on acquiring new users
and so yeah i generally lead the product overall
the product is is really interesting to me and
it especially interests me as someone who's
working on it because you're getting like
constant exposure to completely new ideas
i guess it's every week that you release uh
so it is every week and so you're like
getting this really deep overview of these
different categories over and over and over
again and you have to sort of learn it all
each week right so how what is your process
for for um going through these brand new
industries each week and learning uh
and being able to to share about them
yeah so it's it's funny because a lot of people
ask us about our process because they want to
replicate it and it's really really hard
because there isn't like a step-by-step
like do this and then after that you find out
this and then because you know that you do this
because if you're really trying to identify trends
that other people aren't aware of you have to go
through it through abnormal means and those can be
anything from one of the things we like to train
our analysts to do is just to spot opportunity in
places that um they basically spot opportunity in
everyday things right so if you ever listen to
my first million podcast they show how they do
this often where you know you'll be driving along
the side of the road and you see a patch of grass
let's say and you're like most people will
just drive and not notice that patch of grass
but someone with a keen eye for like why does this
thing exist which really is like the question that
uncovers a lot of industries or a lot of trends
um would be like why does that patch of grass
exist and also like does someone tend to this
patch of grass and if so who does that and then
if someone's paying for this like how much are
they willing to pay for this and why right and
you just start to ask questions about all the
things that you see in the world and as you do
that you start to realize like oh there's this
thing that a lot of people just glance over that
actually is maybe not interesting but at times
extremely interesting right and so you we do that
often in terms of just the things in our everyday
lives the things that our friends talk about the
things that you might hear on a podcast or in a
newsletter and then we try to augment everything
that we do with some sort of data so there are
certain data sources that we pretty consistently
go to so things like you know google trends is an
obvious one but also things like ahrefs like if
if a company has an increasing number of backlinks
like what is that saying about the interest
towards that company something like sensor tower
or app annie there's tons of different um data
sources that we always try to look to to validate
anything that we predict but really it i know it's
like not the answer a lot of people are looking
for but it's really training people to look for
opportunities and things that are that everyone
has access to but aren't necessarily questioning
i love thinking it reminds me of something
that david perell talks about where
it's like look at the things that don't make
sense and then ask questions about them and
follow that rabbit hole until you can't follow
it anymore so i think that that produces a lot
of really interesting insights and in reading
and evaluating taking information from that lens
often leads to really cool um observations about
the world and you know that's what i guess trends
turns into is just the the end of that rabbit hole
of these um you know surprising or abnormal things
exactly that's what we try to do
so i have a question here uh sort of about like
i see myself like being totally fascinated by
trends but also being like afraid of it
because you know you're a serial maker in
the sense of like you have a ton of projects
that you can complete very very quickly
and you're constantly exposing yourself to
new ideas do you ever get like derailed by
the trends like tempted to just throw out what
you're doing and you see a captivating idea and
you just want to run with it like how does that
relationship work with everyone inside the company
also being the type of person to be like oh
my god this is amazing like like they're at an
entrepreneurial company doing entrepreneurial work
and then someone's like a valuable new opportunity
like how does that kind of work i guess with
yourself or the team it's not just be tempted to
follow like eat all your own cooking or
follow all the advice you're giving out
yeah it's it's hard sometimes especially because
within the community itself you see people who
take ideas that we've written about in the
past and create incredible businesses and
you're like what am i doing like why did i
not create that business that i wrote about
or you know why don't i create a business today
based on the thing that we just wrote about um
so it can be very very difficult but i would
say something that i've also recognized over
time is that at least personally i can't speak
for my other co-workers like i'm not in a rush
um to create so i will like almost undoubtedly go
create a business who knows that if it'll succeed
or not but i will go create a business probably
around something i've learned about within trends
or at least within with the knowledge of how to
create a business through through this job but i'm
not in a rush right like do i need to do it today
no would i actually benefit from learning more in
this job or other jobs in the interim until i find
an idea that i think i'm uniquely equipped for
yes right so that's really how i'm thinking about
it where actually i talked about this on a podcast
recently i i was working on social media for a
company years ago and the woman had she was i
think probably like 35 or something like that and
she had worked in industry for those probably 15
years after college and had just started her
job and she was such an incredible ceo like i
still to this day i think one of the best ceos
or you know leaders that i've personally worked
with and i asked her i was like how did you become
such a good ceo like you seem so knowledgeable so
empathetic so so strategic as well and she was
like well steph i spent 15 years getting paid
to learn from people right so a lot of people i
think who are young think that you know they hear
the college dropout stories or the zuck stories or
things like that and they think you know i have to
get started today and sure there are absolutely
stories where people start with little experience
and succeed but i also think there are so many
other stories where other people have spent a long
time learning getting paid to learn enjoying
ideally right i also enjoy my job at trends
and then when the timing is right when you have
the right kind of like uh that right skill set
then going and jumping in into you know the
lake or whatever just like jump going for it
so that's how i'm thinking about it personally
and it does take some amount of restraint to not
go and want to start a company every day but i
also find that i've written about like not needing
to quit your job to make my ability to work my
job and then also kind of like tink around on the
side help satisfy some of that as well i've also
heard you talk about how it makes you not have the
fear and urgency for any side project to work and
like that keeps the intrinsic motivation for a lot
of them alive yeah exactly so people often ask me
like how do you manage to do so much and you know
part of it is that i just like working a lot but
also i get i enjoy my job which is something that
i think not everyone can say and then outside
of that i only choose to work on things that
i actually am excited about as well right and so
if you don't have both of those things true then
you probably are not you're probably going to burn
out a lot faster and to your point i can not only
probably work on more things because i am working
on them outside of my core job and i enjoy them
but i can also do them in ways that are more
satisfying right because i have this financial
stability for my job and then i don't have to
worry about if i go create a project which many
of my many of my projects have not made any money
i don't care about that though right i'm just like
i want to create a directory of untranslatable
words is there any financial you know is this
gonna go anywhere for me probably not but am i
going to enjoy it yes and so i'm going to do it
right versus if you don't have that financial
backing then the decisions you make are probably
going to be a little more skewed towards how do
i make money versus how do i as i said earlier in
the podcast follow my curiosities or things that
i actually want to do even if no one's paying me
yeah i think that's amazing one thing i was
going to say earlier is the you said something
about constraints and i think that one thing that
you've set up um and talked about is seasonality
in your life so like you sort of have this guard
these guard rails for yourself of like okay well
during this period of time i'm going to be working
at trends and maybe you have some sort of like
end date where that's when you'll reevaluate
and if it everything still aligns with your
goals and you're able to be happy like you
you can go through another season right and
and it's just that concept of seasonality i think
is very important for people to understand and to
be able to do important work over long periods of
time yeah and i love your point about like just
constantly asking is something serving me right
whether it's like a relationship or a job and
if it is there's no reason to you know i think a
lot of quote-unquote millennials i'm one of them
like to hop around to many different jobs
because they're like oh i need to gain
this experience at many different places or i
need to like explore a lot more than i exploit
but i think it's just about asking like is this
serving me and i spent three years at a job before
this and i quit when it was no longer serving me
and i plan to stay at trends for the you know time
period that quote unquote serving me and my unique
needs and goals and i think that's just important
where a lot of people you know i find people kind
of go to the extremes where either they stay a job
forever and they never question that or they're
constantly feeling like they need to like hop
around and they're never satisfied um and it's all
about just identifying your clear needs and goals
and then just asking like with everything
that you focus a large amount of your time
on is this serving my needs today yes or no and
then being okay with it for a period of time and
then evaluating on you know at whatever timeline
is appropriate for you right and that's the
important piece is we're evaluating on a timeline
so are you do you think you're constantly asking
that question or do you think that you are um
waiting for a period and then that's when you ask
that questions because i think if you're if you're
constantly asking it might be a negative thing
yeah exactly there's a balance to everything
so i don't have like a rigid timeline but i do
think it's every you know couple times a year
just like sit back and reflect on your goals i
think that's why like quarterly is a good time
period to be like am i still making decisions
that like at the end of the day if i continue
this for five years would make me happy and if
that's not true that's when you maybe you don't
even need to make life-altering decisions but
where you start to just re-pivot yourself or
reorient yourself in the direction that you
wanted to be in in the first place because it
can just be easy to slide right and you all of
a sudden like if you if you don't pay attention
for a year's worth of time where you're like oh
my god like how did i end up here or like why did
i spend six months on this thing and i never even
wanted that outcome and so i think there's no
like rated time but i do encourage people to have
whether it's yearly or quarterly-ish goals
that they go and re-evaluate every so often
well well uh what are you gonna say kyle i was
gonna transition us to an idea segment but if that
was what you're gonna do go for it i was gonna
do the same so there we go a plus coordination
right there but we want to transition now
and to actually not just getting people
excited by the idea of trends but actually
discussing a few uh we heard on the my first
million podcast you brought six pages of notes and
they had only time for page one so hopefully with
a lot of unexplored ideas uh in the trend space i
don't know if you want to jump right into a couple
exciting ideas or if kyle wants to feed an idea
he has and get your take on it if any come to mind
you can start out all right that's good i can
pull up the document i need to find it that i
i really want yeah i've got two ideas the first is
parking lot alternatives so fifty to sixty percent
of downtown's um like scarce resource of land is
dedicated to um vehicles and vehicle servicing i
think over time with autonomous vehicles um that
percentage of land that's needed for vehicles will
will decrease significantly ultimately
probably to like around zero percent because
if the car is driving itself um and the car you
know we only use our car for about 10 of our time
um and so if it was driving itself all the
time and could drive to a parking lot like
we just wouldn't need this space to be dedicated
to vehicles and so what i want to think about is
parking lot um alternatives but what are we going
to do with this land in the future and and how
how do we use it in such a way that's
like native to the um to the the structure
and also produces some sort of you know high
productivity um thing for people yeah i think
it's a really interesting idea i don't know what
the answer is in terms of what it will be used for
but you're absolutely right that i think a lot of
different land or real estate will be repurposed
the same way that we saw the sharing economy
for uber or or homes you just think about really
land was created to like service particular
needs for people and to your point like even
just consider how much fewer cars will be on the
road now that people will start working remotely
like so that's a need that people you already saw
during the pandemic decreased and probably will
never come back quite to the extent that existed
before okay so then now there's less demand for
parking spaces or for space on the road perhaps so
what is that used for in terms of what i actually
think will replace it it's hard to say you've
seen even throughout the pandemic things like
like pop-up things like pop-up stores or pop-up
um events in those spaces and i think that
what you're gonna see is real estate really
being fractionalized right so in the past
like everything was everything was used for one
purpose and what i'm really interested in is you
see things like if you've ever heard of cody work
that's a company that basically is allowing people
to turn their homes into co-working spaces i
also i'm from toronto i've seen a club there
that during the night this is before pandemic
was a club and then during the day it's actually
a co-working space right and so you're going to
probably find people fractionalizing real estate
similar ish to what airbnb does today or even if
you think about uber that's kind of a fractional
ownership structure where someone owns the car
but half the time they're using it for their own
needs and then half the time they're using it
for other people's needs right and so i think
you're going to start to see this with real estate
i don't have an answer specific to parking spaces
but i think you're almost certainly going to see
people fractionalize real estate across the board
yeah hopefully it's fractionalized on a blockchain
that's an area that i'm very interested in is the
intersection of real estate and centralized
finance but i think one uh specific one that
i think about is like drone charging stations and
um you know i guess like high density areas where
the parking lot has um like it's like an aired out
parking lot so they could charge there they could
fly there and then fly out uh that's one concept
that i think about as like sort of fitting this
idea but there's gonna be so much um open parking
space that there's going to have to be like so
many new um use cases for it and then yeah and
tied to that when you think about the economics
yeah i mean there's tons of different ways
that can be used but you almost certainly
are going to see right now the reason that
there's so many parking spaces because there's
enough demand for it and that demand pushes
the prices up for those co-working spaces right
now that we're you'll probably see over the next
decade less demand for those co-working spaces
which means that people who own co-working lot
or sorry parking spaces sorry parking spaces when
they when you see less demand for the parking
spaces the prices will go down for parking the
lots will actually not be able to satisfy
you know the like economics of what they've
paid and them wanting to keep it and then you're
gonna see some some sort of company i don't know
if it's like a commercial building company i don't
know if it's like uh uh supermarket i don't know
what company would take these over but
they're gonna use that space and be able to
buy it for much cheaper because the economics for
the parking lots will just no longer make sense
as to like what will take over it's it's very hard
to say but you almost certainly will see that many
of them will start getting taken over because
the economics just won't make sense anymore
incentives and markets there you go um so the next
one that i've got and i'll just move through this
quickly and the one that we were talking about
before we started recording is i had it last night
it's like basically tons of boomers are retiring
they've got small businesses um and they don't
want to necessarily just sell it off to somebody
who doesn't really care about it there are a lot
of zoomer entrepreneurs who are willing to work
hard but don't have necessarily the capital to go
buy a business um and they don't have the skills
necessary to to just like start it on their own
so my idea would be like a matchmaking between
these boomer entrepreneur entrepreneurs and these
zoomer entrepreneurs getting them together sort of
doing like an apprenticeship um type of schedule
where the uh the young entrepreneur will work
with the boomer over a certain number of years
and then from the beginning it's like guaranteed
seller financing so it's sort of like an income
share agreement but um in a completely different
way and that in the end the zoomer takes control
of the business owns it and the boomer knows
that it was left in good hands and somebody that
um knows how their business works from from start
to finish because they taught them themselves
potential college replacements alternative gotcha
so how would the income share agreement work where
you basically would have the the like young
person pay in theory in the future like get
pay a percentage of their yeah so income running
the business or can you explain that part yeah so
i meant um that the guaranteed seller financing
would sort of be like an income share agreement
where um you know based on the performance of the
business the um seller or the boomer who had just
apprenticed this person over a period of
time would have guaranteed income um you know
based on whatever the profit of the business
was and not just the income of the um the young
entrepreneur but based on how well the boomer did
at teaching them and how well the the zoomer is
at making this business run determines how much
money the boomer is going to get in retirement
gotcha so i think yeah it wouldn't be a
full transition of ownership that like the
the boomer could still retain some equity or some
sort of like residual income from the business
mm-hmm yeah so i think i think you you have some
interesting ideas here what i would probably say
about the structure is that maybe you'd want to
flip it and you would actually have more of an
income share agreement on the like
individual side where if you're like
a kid thinking about college and you're thinking
well i could go to college or you know and come
out with a ton of debt or i could perhaps go
work for this company for not very much money
or more of an equity structure than like a salary
structure and this company of this boomer you know
that they probably want to sell but you have
like a two-year agreement where that you're
going to like work your way up and it's almost
like an accelerated internship where you start
as like knowing nothing and by the end you're
actually like gearing up to lead this business
and at the end you have the opportunity but on
both ends to say like do we want this like do we
want this person to continue like fully taking
over the business or you know again the boomer
could retain some equity but um i think that
actually aligns the incentives a little more
to like this person is going to want to learn
worst case they're going to learn a lot about
running a business get paid okay and have some
equity in this business and then if it doesn't
work out at the end of the two years like they
leave and they have this incredible experience
and then the boomer is like look if worst case
it doesn't work out and i just had someone
work for me and and learn from me for two years
and i still retain full ownership and then if of
course if it's a good match then they'll you
know facilitate an agreement between the two
of them after that two-year period or it can be a
shorter period potentially but i think that makes
more sense because i could see the boomer at the
beginning being like why would i like why would
i give away a lot of my company up front if i
if i'm unsure about this person it gives them
time to actually figure out if it's aligned mm-hmm
yeah yeah like a vesting schedule um and the point
would be to align incentives right to make this
um this character of a zoomer act as a principle
throughout their time as an apprentice so
that you know they've got a clear end goal um
and that they can reach it if they work hard
enough and if they make smart enough decisions
and hopefully those decisions are incentivized
to where they act as if they're already the
owner so that um you know the business
benefits from that dramatically um yeah
i mean i think you can just yeah sorry go ahead
i was gonna say and it's in such a way that um
you know the boomer is not risking much
at the beginning based on just like
the id like this character they're not giving
anything away at the beginning they're only giving
things away as you know good decisions are made
and as the person continues to prove themselves
yeah i think you could just position something
like that as like an alternative mba there's
tons of different companies that kind of say
that they're an alternative mba but at the end
of the day the structure is very similar right
they're like providing some sort of education
like classical education to a group of people
um and it may be slightly different in terms
of like the cases that it covers or you know maybe
having a little more hands-on effort but you could
basically restructure it and be like this is the
like new age mba and instead of going to a zoom
class or even in a person class and learning about
these case studies you're on the job and you just
have this like two year period instead of paying
250k for your mba you're actually getting paid
let's say 100k throughout that period and so i
think you could just almost market something like
that as an alternative mba if you're able to find
the right companies that people can learn from
and then the right types of people right because
that's really the issue this is basically like
no matter how you marketed a two-sided
marketplace and you want to make sure
that you would be able to find really high um
class or not high class rather like high caliber
caliber students or people who are interested in
potentially doing something like an mba and then
high caliber companies as well that people could
actually learn from because i think one part of
that idea that would be very difficult to
execute is finding those high caliber um
those high caliber inputs on both sides
that's the difficult part of all marketplaces
well i'm completely out of ideas so there you
go we're going to pass the mic back over to
you then and see what uh you might have for us
a couple of them here well i'm scrolling through
um some of the stuff that i had in this document
from before one of the things that i so i've been
interested in remote work for a while and i'm
super interested in things that allow you to be
healthy and active while working remotely because
it's extremely hard to do especially i will also
say pandemic work is not like normal remote work
but even outside of that there are all sorts of
cool little gadgets that i found one of them in
particular um i think it's called qb so it's cube
i can never remember how to spell it q u b i i
and it's basically like an under desk elliptical
that you know as you're in your meetings if
you've ever seen like under desk treadmills
um but this is like an underdesk
elliptical that is i'll send it to you guys
that is i'm trying to see the pricing of it i
think it is a couple hundred bucks yeah 250 bucks
and i think there's just gonna be a huge market
for things like this that actually allow you to be
healthy while you know spending your day on
zoom calls um and i we actually looked some
of this stuff up on jungle scout if you guys have
used that tool allows you to see what different
products or amazon photos and stuff amazon exactly
and this product let me just look it up again
is making an insane amount of money on jungle
scout and i wonder just if you kind of go down
the line of different um needs that your
body has whether it's like back support
or whether it's the different gym equipment that
you actually use when you go to the gym like
how can those be integrated natively into
your working environment or your home
and natively i think is important here because
of course you can go by weights you can go buy
a running treadmill but how do you actually like
integrate it into your day because at the end of
the day if i'm sure you guys felt this in your
zoom classes like you'll get through eight hours
and be like what the hell did i do and like why
do i feel so [ __ ] so i wonder if there's other
products that people could create that actually
help um satisfy some of these needs so like active
sitting as a as a category for active passive
consumption physically active passive consumption
yeah i mean exactly i just think that like how
do you make it such that you know starting with a
question someone doesn't feel like crap at the end
of it like eight eight hour stretch or zoom calls
and then working backwards from that i think
there's several different opportunities within
that qb is like one that seems to be doing super
super well but i feel like there's probably other
solutions in the the things that standing desks
that we like balance that's that's another thing
oh yeah balance boards exactly and i think this
has a lot of positive externalities potentially on
remote work and in general and like companies
could be incentivized to purchase this for
their um for the employees because if they feel
better throughout the day and they're they're
more excited and able to you know sit through this
eight hours they're going to produce better work
and you know more revenue for the company
and that's something that you talked about
um on mfm was like remote work benefits and how
i think one of the things you might have said
or i heard it somewhere else was like you know
they're paying 10 to 20 000 per head for their
office space and that that money can be allocated
towards something else and so like a a cubie for
every employee to be able to feel good at the end
of the day is like a no-brainer so it's like what
products are there um that other than just qb that
companies could purchase for i have an idea go for
it assisting with outdoor workspace setup like
help something to system like because that's part
of the well-being is like you're inside and you're
sitting so like being outside but having a good
workstation with proper accommodations and like
some sort of weatherproofness aspect of it whether
it's like a screened-in box or something so like
you can still enjoy it if it's rainy or something
and like not have to you don't have to like
hustle in with like three monitors but you
want the full comfort outdoors so that
could be like an additional side category
yeah tied to what you were saying kyle there's
also some companies very few at this point who
actually paid their employees to get better sleep
so if their employees could show that you know
whether it's an apple watch or an orange that they
were getting like a satisfactory amount of sleep
they were actually getting paid for that um some
may say that's a little intrusive but at the same
time it's exactly what you're what you pointed
out where if you actually can prove through your
product whether it's you know a better bed or a qb
or something something else that actually enriches
your employees lives and health in particular
then it's a no-brainer for these companies to
say well if my employees get better sleep then i
know that their productivity is going to go up 30
and therefore like the extra 5k or whatever i'm
spending is again a no-brainer so i think i think
there's going to be a lot of um a lot of movement
in this space because through additional studies
people are able to tie some of these um ideas
to numbers which they couldn't before right so
you could actually say if people get better sleep
they're x percent more productive or if they are
mentally well they are you know x percent you
know happier at work or things like that so i
think as more studies come out as some of
these like more intangibles in the last
couple decades become tangibles you're gonna
see companies spend a lot more in this area
so that leads me to my next question this
is gonna sort of be a second but like um
satisfactory sleep in terms of like your apple
watch or some app that you use i have found
that when i track my sleep it um objectively
makes it worse because i wake up and it's like
you got 70 and it's like oh well i'm
gonna have a shitty day today because
like my app tells me that i didn't sleep well so
i think that having um delayed um availability
of the data uh for your sleep in a sleep app is a
good idea i tweeted about that a little while ago
um because otherwise like i got a 50 like my
day is shot because my app tells me so but
that leads me to another question
about tracking things in general
and so i know that you are very quantitative and
you track like loads of things about your life
and um how do you do you tread the line of
tracking everything and becoming an automaton
yeah so i think the way that i do do it which
is not going to work for everyone else because
this is just kind of like i've been told by
many other people do it this way do it that
way and when i tried it doesn't work for me so
what i say probably won't work for other people
is to be very specific about the things that you
track but not how you track it and what i mean
by that is i will sit down and i'll say at the
beginning of the year these are like the six or
so things that i want to track relatively daily
and by relatively daily that's important because
at the end of the day what i do is i actually have
a spreadsheet that says like did i like exercise
today did i call my parents did i not that i
do that often but that's like a way for me to
see like oh my god has it been a month and i like
haven't called my parents um but what i don't do
is say exactly at 5 p.m i must enter stuff into
the spreadsheet in fact sometimes i'll go three
or four days without entering anything because
i've forgotten or i'm busy and then you know your
memory is not that terrible you certainly
can't remember what you did two weeks ago
but you can remember what you did three days ago
right and so what i try to do is again be really
diligent about the things that i care about right
in terms of like making sure they are part of some
tracking system but not being so specific
about exactly like this needs to be tracked
at this time because then i think it can get a
little intrusive until into your creativity and
and like ability to just like live your life um
and i also try not to make it be like you know
some people will set goals and say i absolutely
need to work out four times a week and what i do
is more so use data as a feedback system and less
of like a you must do this rigidly at like this
many times a week right so sometimes i'll look
and i'll be like oh damn like i didn't work out
for like two weeks and that's really terrible and
that'll just be like a kick in the butt to be like
you know get back to things that you care about
and that benefit your life but i won't sit there
and be like you know i absolutely need to work out
on this day and this day and this day so it's a
balance for everyone and i do think that you can
skew too far in either direction where you're not
tracking it all and then you really have no clue
how you're doing and then the other side being
like we're tracking absolutely everything in a
very very rigid way which is i think a little too
again intrusive to your ability to just live your
life and have a little fluidity there so that's
what i do but again i don't know if if it works
for everyone and i think it speaks like a pretty
powerful principle as far as like behavior change
and habit design i think one thing a lot of people
get wrong is you know everyone has the temporary
motivation to like start tracking something or
like get serious about doing a goal and they
don't purposely build slack into the system
up front so that when they break they become
demoralized but if you set like at the outset
kyle and some of his friends had this thing
where they did like compounding daily habits
so like they had seven habits they wanted to do
and it was a good day if they did four of them and
like depending on the day you could choose your
four and so on the days you're like you don't want
to get your workout in but you're like oh read a
little bit like that's another type of system and
i think it's way better to do something like that
or like for a journal for example i think it's way
better to journal three times a week for an entire
year than a journal every day for a month and
then not have anything for those 11 months exactly
because to your point when someone like if they're
trying to get fit and they do some crazy workout
for three months let's say and and they do it
consistently throughout that period sure certain
habits may be instilled throughout that period
but at the end of the period if they don't want
to continue doing exactly that they don't know the
gray area right it's either like this crazy
workout routine or nothing right and there's no
normalcy baked into their habits and no one
works out every day some people do but like
i certainly don't and so if i try to work
out every single day for 30 days which is
actually what i did in february well guess
what happened in march as soon as march hit
i didn't work out for like two weeks because if i
wasn't doing it as you said full on i wasn't doing
it at all and so having some of that slack built
in is really important so you're actually building
a normalized habit that you can continue for a
long period of time and not like as they say like
sprint at the beginning of a marathon exactly yeah
i think that this aligns well with something that
vitalik buterin wrote about like the difference
between a convex person and a concave person
and now some people just exist in the extremes
and some people can exist in the middle and i
think existing in the middle is actually better
but throughout my life i've definitely existed on
the extremes of of the thing like you're saying
i did 75 hard which was a three-month workout
routine where you work out twice a day and it's
like okay well when 75 days is over i'm going to
drink a bottle of wine and not work out for a week
like yeah and i totally believe that um being in
the middle is better but for me for some reason
it's just easier to be on the extremes it's just
like a more normal way of living my life and i
think that i should uh probably break that habit
well i think it depends how you like what you're
actually trying to achieve right so sometimes
you actually do need to do a 75 hard to like get
back into motion right to be like okay i'm just
like i need a forcing function here and then also
something that i've written and talked about is
this idea of you can only focus on so many things
in your life right and so if you really are trying
to focus consistently on like 12 different things
in your life like guess what you're probably gonna
fail at all of them so i do think there's an
argument to focusing on a couple things at a
time and then slowly like bringing them into your
life to some degree where like maybe you do a 75
heart to like remind yourself that you like can
exercise and you can run and it's not so bad and
then after that you chill out and like you you
exercise more normally so i do think there's
an argument to focusing uh intensely on something
for a period of time i just don't think it's
sustainable to do it forever right but there
is like an argument to do it as like a forcing
function to bring something back into your life
i completely agree with that i want to transition
now we're in our last 10 minutes or so to asking
you some questions about the digital nomad
lifestyle uh because as i told you graduating
college very soon and that's something that kind
of ever since i first learned about it freshman
sophomore it's like that's the plan i'm gonna
go do that when i graduate and there's a lot of
competing opinions on the internet that you know
everyone does it for like a year and they're like
you don't build community and you kind of like
no one knows your name and like it kind of is not
all typed up to be but it's something that you've
kind of lived for like five years which is a lot
maybe even longer so what's your overall take
on when it's a good idea when it's
not such a good idea or how to do it
like the right way what's like your
prescription for someone who's curious about it
like wants to avoid the pitfalls yeah i mean the
pitfalls that people mentioned are accurate and
one of the things that i think a lot of people who
have been nomadic for a while dislike about you
know whether it's like a vox article or a forbes
article is that it's either like digital nomadism
is the future and like the best way of life or
it's like digital nomadism is for self-obsessed
millennials that can't like get a job right
it's either like this is amazing and the best
thing for the future or terrible and like no one
should do it and actually you'll hate it if you
try it and it's in reality somewhere in the middle
and it also heavily depends on like who someone
is and what they strive towards themselves or for
example like are you more habitual or are you not
do you need routine do you not how much do
you rely on community how much do you actually
you know are you more of like a nomad where
you enjoy you know doing things on your own
so it really depends and i know that's a shitty
answer but i will say as you asked a prescription
is basically if you've ever heard of the explore
exploit um conundrum yeah exactly so basically
it's this idea of where within life you're always
going to be wondering like should i go try new
things or should i actually like leverage the
things that i've tried and i know i like and
enjoy and that's always a trade-off whether it's
in a relationship where they're like wow this
relationship is really great but like what else
could be out there or whether you're in a city
and you're like man i've been in the city for five
days and i have three left should i just go to the
restaurants that i know i like or like this random
thing on the corner that i've been wondering about
so it's everywhere in life but in particular
with nomading i think it's really important where
one of the best things that you can do is
go explore the world for a period of time
right and it's this whole explore idea where you
need to learn what is out there and you need to
like find out what you don't know right because
if you're always in let's say you guys are in
alabama if you stay in alabama your whole life
you'll be in that mindset the same way if you've
only dated one person your whole life you're like
what else is out there right like even if i enjoy
this like you're always gonna be wondering and so
you need to do yourself a service to go explore
to go see the world and again learn what you don't
know right to experience all the things that are
like this mystery in your head to some degree if
you never experienced them and go do that and then
after you do that for i think most people can only
do that for around a year or so without getting
pretty exhausted because again i think the main
thing that some people are trying to articulate
when they um say digital nomadism isn't what
it typed out to be is that humans really really
strive for a couple things in the end which is
community some form of routine it doesn't need
to be like a rigid routine but something that is
consistent that they can rely on and when you go
and you travel to a new place every week or every
couple days like that's one really exhausting but
it you cannot establish that routine and that
community which are really really important to
like humans as creatures and so my advice and
this is basically what i did actually is to go
and travel for a period of time for me it was
probably around two years of quite rapid traveling
so actually i think that was too long but in
any case go do it for a period of time whatever
works for you and go experience that almost as
some people say like get it out of your system
and i actually think that's like an accurate
phrase because it's really like as i said if
you don't do it it's going to be like this thing
in your body that you're like i want to do this
and i'm curious about it and if you never do it
like it's always going to be in the back your head
so go do that and then after you've gone and
experienced things as part of that experience
also consider like what you liked about different
places that's really essential don't just like
blindly travel and be like oh this is so fun be
like i want to go to x place because i've heard
like their culture is really good or why place
because their internet's really good and they
have a lot of digital nomads or zed plays because
um i don't know maybe like i have family there
right there's all different types of reasons
why you would go to different places and then
jot down like what you actually like about
places the same way that if you're trying to
evaluate a you know your future partner you're
like well i was in this relationship and i
really liked this aspect of it but i didn't like
this right and and therefore i think i need this
in my future relationships right so as you go
travel then you're really trying to just discern
what do i need in a place that i want to like
not necessarily settle down permanently that i
want to spend a lot of time in and that's what
i think a lot of nomads do without maybe even
consciously doing is they go and they explore
a bunch and then they decide where they want to
exploit and exploit in this case it's not actually
exploiting the place of course but in the term
of explore and exploit where do i want to spend
more time and really settle down in and so what
a lot of people end up doing is going to the like
digital nomad hubs like chengu or chiang mai or
medellin or lisbon and that's because at the end
of the day as i mentioned i think the commonality
is that people are just looking for community and
up until the pandemic that was one of the only pla
those were some of the only places where you could
get really really solid community quickly um and
also just have your like basic needs really easily
met as a nomad like good weather good internet um
cheap cost of living things like that what i
think you might see is that those things expand
or those list of cities expand after the pandemic
because they're just gonna be so many more nomads
and so many more nomad hubs that kind of are
built relatively overnight because it took
literally a decade to even build up the community
that exists in chengu and chiang mai and
in lisbon at the digital nomad community i mean um
because it was like a slow evolution right of like
just a couple people becoming slightly more
nomadic over time and then obviously the pandemic
has made just so many more people have access to
this lifestyle so i think you are going to see a
lot more of them but to get back to your question
of like a prescription if someone is thinking like
i do want to be nomadic i want to see the world i
want to live a flexible lifestyle because that's
really what nomadism is like you are able to
be anywhere that you want and that's that's it
right and if that means you want to stay
in alabama for the rest of your life great
but but if it does right or if if i
wanted to stay in toronto great but
all it means is that i can be exactly where i want
to be right and so to get back to the question
go explore for a period of time go have
fun go see the world learn a little bit
along the way and then slowly it doesn't
even have to be like an overnight switch
probably what you're going to find is that you're
going to slow down and focus more on a couple
areas and in fact the most common thing that i see
of permanent nomads these days minus the pandemic
is spending around 50 50 in places so they will
have like a place that they they really like
which is more close to like their family let's say
like if they're from europe they'll spend maybe
half the year or a season in europe and then the
rest of the year and somewhere like bali um but
of course it depends on the person but really
that that would be my prescription for anyone
thinking about it well i know you had a question
but can i jump in super quick with one real quick
like a no yeah it's a quick one uh that's
incredible that was such a good answer that
was a really good answer and it just sparked more
questions i wanted to ask so i have like you know
saving enough savings to take a couple months
and like have a pure gist vacation or i could
like take a remote job and like work and play at
the same time like has it taken away like what
do you advise like full vacation full remote
partial does it take away from the experience
to be half working while you're traveling or does
that not get in the way and it's actually better
because like you're not just drinking margaritas
16 hours a day i think you should experience both
i've done both so when i graduated college
i went for four months and traveled as a
backpacker i didn't even bring a laptop you don't
need to do it for four months necessarily but i i
had so much fun and i think anyone who's done
a backpacking trip like that will say the same
so go do that for a period of time if you have
the like finances do that um even if it's just
for like two to three weeks go once the pandemic
is subsided like go book a trip to thailand or
cambodia or something it's so incredibly fun
um but obviously that's not sustainable i think
again sometimes you see people in like and i have
seen this like we're in southeast asia and you see
someone who you're like oh my god you've been
a backpacker for like 14 years and they quite
honestly don't look very happy or fulfilled so
i do think there's an argument to doing that
for a short period of time enjoying it you're
young like go experience that but then after that
there is also equal amount of fulfillment in
going and creating things and you know building
up your life in in different ways so once you're
done and you can intersperse between the two
right as well as it's not like one or the other
but more of your time is likely gonna be spent
as a nomad where you are actually working
and that is a very different experience
because you're basically living somewhere
right and you're and you are for most of
the week spending time on your computer however
you work and then very little time actually spent
going and doing touristy things but i will
say the more that you travel around the more
inc or sorry the less inclined you are to want
to do touristy things because a lot of it whether
it's in one country or another does start to
seem quite similar if you've traveled a lot
yeah i think i'm noticing that i know louis has
had that experience when he was studying abroad
in thailand um but i have a question for you based
around something that you've created which is like
that um i can't remember what it's called but
it's or maybe it's how to be great like there's
one side that's investing there's one side that's
spending time and this framework has come up a
couple times in the podcast and something that i
really like when looking at the world is just like
what is investing time what is spending
time what's the difference um and i've
come to this conclusion that activities that
could be spending time by yourself can be
investing time when you're with another person
um and you're investing in that that mutual
relationship with that with that person so my
question is like how have you found or the best
ways to maximize return on invested time um
with relational relationship time investments
yeah so what's interesting about most
goals is that like if i want to learn
to code it's like very straightforward
i'm just like put in this number of hours
by the end of that if you really put in those
hours you will know how to code relationships are
you know much less analytical and they really just
do take time and investment like there's no like
formula to building a relationship and that's
actually something that i've had to learn over
the last i've been in my current relationship
for like a year and a half now and prior to that
i was so analytical about everything right as you
guys know like like tracking if i'm exercising or
calling my parents or flossing and it's in this
relationship been something i've had to learn
where it's like you actually just have to like not
be so analytical about it and also not just like
allocate time to it but like talk if you're
trying to build a relationship you need to
like talk to your partner and find out what they
need and it's less so just like inputs outputs
so i don't know if i have a great answer for
you other than whatever you're trying to build
whether it's like a romantic relationship or
a relationship with your family is just making
time for it um and then um from there i think
if you're struggling in a relationship also
just like asking someone what they need
um so i again i don't know if i have
it's a tough question for sure um but we've got
just two more quick questions for you um the first
is you know we saw her tweet obviously we've
got a podcast coming up with you so it's like
wow i hope she doesn't die after this but she's
got something that she wants to say so let's say
that today is your last day and you can transmit a
message to a billion people what do you tell them
so my i think if i've learned anything in the last
couple years that i think i've actually like not
just learned through some book but actually lived
is this idea that you can truly design your life
and it doesn't matter like where you're from
what like income you have what whether you have
kids or not i truly think that anyone can design
their life and it takes time right like where i
am today to probably five to ten years of time
of like investing into where i wanted to be um
but i think a lot of people will make and i'll
probably get some people who disagree with me
but will make excuses for why they cannot design
their life in some way they'll say i have kids and
you don't know what it's like to have kids that's
true i don't know what it's like to have kids or
they'll say you know i have this job which is not
your job and therefore like you don't know what
it's like to have this work requirement but what
they don't realize is that someone like me used to
actually work for jobs and used to have a bunch
of student debt and used to you know commute two
hours a day to work and used to like all these
things right and so i think that if i could
encourage people to do one thing is to take a step
back imagine what i mentioned earlier this idea
where there's a bunch of hills and really think
about like what hill you want to be on and then
start making the steps towards moving to that hill
and the first part of that journey may be downhill
right because naturally you're going to be on some
hill already and you need to like traverse down it
in order to get to the next hill so that
would really be my uh i don't like the word
advice sometimes but my advice to people who are
thinking like oh i'm not happy in my life for some
reason and i really want to be doing something
else but i feel like i can't do it i feel like
of course there are constraints in life but i
think more often than not people use constraints
as crutches to say why they can't do something
and i think it's actually really empowering to
just think like you know what like why can't
i design my life exactly how i want it to be
and i think i would just encourage people to
do that that's a beautiful answer well steph
we are very grateful to you for coming on if
our listeners really enjoyed your content as
i'm sure they will where should we send
them to find you and to find your work
i guess um twitter is where i'm most uh active so
steph smith i o and then if people are interested
they can find my other work at stephsmith.io
subscribe to the trends follow our blog buy book
he's been a great guest thank you very much steph
we really really appreciate it and that wraps up
our conversation with steph smith i really really
enjoyed it um three quick takeaways for me the
first one is you can design your life no matter
who you are no matter where you're at you can
take stock of where you're at and you can
completely change and it's just that simple
but i mean the advice and those words are
something that i think are really powerful
the second is to reevaluate things at a regular
interval so i think that you don't want to
reevaluate things every day you don't want to be
you know like i'm walking up this hill and i look
around and i'm like freaking out every day about
whether or not this is the right hill you should
i think place like sort of roadblocks
where at that roadblock you know
when you get to that roadblock on this hill
that's when you're going to be like okay
let me look around today and i think that sort of
takes off some of the pressure um that comes with
having to make that decision is putting it off
into the future and knowing that when it comes
you'll be ready to to tackle it and look around
and then the third one so our first question was
who are you without your career and i think that
just that idea in general is super powerful and
i've been thinking about it recently and when
someone asks me what i do i'm like well i do this
podcast i'm in school and it's like well that
doesn't really tell them who i am specifically
and so you know i need to work on that and i
think that a lot of people probably will too
and those are my takeaways thank you kyle i
enjoy those and have some similar ones but
as always some similar and some different ones a
couple things i'm taking away from this episode uh
we sometimes might be spreading an ethos that jobs
are the worst thing in the world and the only way
to have a happy satisfied life and to do anything
of value is to be an entrepreneur it's clearly
clearly clearly not the case and not at all uh
the message that we want to send i want to send
the message of there's a lot of different ways to
thrive in this world and we hope to expose you to
different ways of doing that and hopefully an idea
from the podcast resonates with you and encourages
you to pursue one of those hills when you're at
an appropriate planning interval so you can design
the life that you want to have for yourself uh she
gave a really really powerful case study of just
someone who has not been an entrepreneur but has
been paid to learn over and over and over again
and is very confident in herself that if and
when the right idea strikes she's gonna have
the network and the skills uh to succeed at one of
them not necessarily the first one but one of them
so i think that's a really powerful reminder for
those of us like myself who get caught up in the
trap of entrepreneurship immediately is the only
viable way to do entrepreneurship second takeaway
uh she really spoke to me right at the end about
the prescription for remote work talking about
how if it's a bug you know you kind of get the
itch to travel and it's not going to go away
until you scratch it so i've kind of like you know
it's not every day right it's not like every day
i'm like oh i got to do this but like every two
or three weeks i'm like i'd really love to try
this whole digital nomad thing and it's probably
gonna keep popping up every two or three weeks
until i actually try it so explore exploit try it
see how you like it that's definitely something
i'm going to pursue with more confidence and
then like you said about lifestyle design but
more broadly in general it's just such
a powerful thinking tool that if you
exist in the frame of being what are reasons
i can't do this you'll come up with a million
excuses but if you instead force yourself to
entertain it's uncomfortable it goes against
what you've been taught and it like makes you
often have to take uncomfortable action reasons
you can do this right for me reasons i can go be
a digital nomad and live whatever i want to do uh
you're actually that's the only time you're ever
going to come up with the answers is if you let
yourself think about the reasons why you can so
that's all i have to say about our episode with
steph i really hope you enjoyed it as much as
we enjoyed having steph on the podcast if you
appreciate the work that myself and kyle are doing
on the show we would really be grateful for you
to show some support that could come in a number
of ways you can go here on apple podcasts leave
a rating or review if you're watching on youtube
you can like comment subscribe do all those things
and if you have friends that like podcasts you can
tell them about the lewis and kyle show recommend
this episode any episode specific one uh you help
us grow the show the bigger the show is the cooler
people say yes to coming on and the more you get
cool episodes it's pretty awesome so help us out
if we've helped you out and we'll see you in
a week with the next episode have a good one